Contact

07038637271 (Mobile) ugberodavid@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/davidugbero-81a491141 (LinkedIn) www.techydavid.com (Personal)

Top Skills

REST APIs Development
Python (Programming Language)
Nginx Plus

Languages

English (Professional Working)

Certifications

Build REST APIs with Python and Flask

Advanced REST APIs with Python and Flask

Honors-Awards

Coding Challenge Winner in Edo State, Nigeria.

David Ugbero

Software Developer and Server Administrator.

Summary

Software development is my passion! I am a driven tech lover dedicated to learning, creating and teaching programming or enlightening enthusiasts about technology in my society. With 3 years of total experience, my expertise includes:

- Microservices-architectured REST APIs.
- Nginx and Nginx Plus.
- Docker and Kubernetes.
- Linux Server Administration.
- · DigitalOcean droplets and AWS instances management.
- · Managed Databases.

Experience

Victoria Island, Lagos

AIICO Capital Ltd Information Technology Intern October 2019 - January 2020 (4 months)

AIICO Capital Ltd is a leading secure investments management firm in Nigeria, a multi-asset manager that provides portfolio and fund management services and also fixed income investments.

I worked in it's IT department and ensured:

- Smooth running of all systems, networks and connections.
- All computers are joined to the domain controller.
- Systems setup and network troubleshooting for staffs.
- · Server files update.

In the time being, I also built an Investment App for the company to help with many manual processes..

One Kiosk Africa Software Developer September 2019 - October 2019 (2 months) Ikoyi, Lagos One Kiosk Africa seeks to redefine the E-commerce retail market by improving efficiency using technology to ensure deliver is within 20-59 minutes.

During my time there,

- I led the technical department being it's Tech Team Lead.
- I supervised the development of the company's main software product.

Treskaro Systems & Solutions
Tech Team Lead
December 2018 - July 2019 (8 months)
Benin

Treskaro Systems & Solutions is a Business Supports Services Provider situated in the South South side of Nigeria.

I led it's IT department during my time there. Our flagship product,
 Ecoconnect App, a mobile app that seeks to simplify and incentivise waste disposal, made an impact in the city and was made a grant of #500k from the Edo State Govt.

LT Visions Company, Benin-city, Edo state, Nigeria Back End Web Developer April 2017 - July 2017 (4 months) Benin

LT Visions is a Software Company in the University of Benin, Edo State, Nigeria.

- Built a VoIP mobile application that uses Wifi to communicate in a short range.
- Involved in the development of a mobile application similar to YouTube but accessibility is via connection to the company's WiFi.

Education

University of Benin
Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (2016 - 2020)